Guide to the J. Douglas Carroll, Jr. papers, 1938-1985.
Carroll, J. Douglas, Jr. papers, 1938-1985.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
J. Douglas Carroll, Jr. papers, 1938-1985.
4178
J. Douglas Carroll, Jr.
1.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, speeches, lectures, publications, and curriculum vitae.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, speeches, lectures, and publications about transportation issues in regional planning. Also curriculum vitae.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Planning consultant.
Member, International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, speeches, lectures, and publications about transportation issues in regional planning. Also curriculum vitae.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Carroll, J. Douglas, Jr.; Lambda Alpha International.
Subjects:
Urban transportation.; City planning.; Real property--Economic aspects.
Form and Genre Terms:
Resumes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Part of Regional Science Archives.
CONTAINER LIST
- Personal, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Carroll Family Genealogy (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Carroll Family Miscellaneous, 1954-1960, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Certificates, 1947, 1951, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "Four Generations of Carrolls" (carbon ts. mss.) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Five Generations of Carrolls" (carbon ts. mss.), Louise Carroll Wade (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Planning Papers, ca. 1926-1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Harvard, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Harvard, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- re: CATS proposal and other, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Land Economics", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Flint Downtown Parking Survey (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Part-time Enrollment of Adults in College Credit Courses, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Articles, papers, reports, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- General Motors Better Highways Contest, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Predicting Local Travel in Urban Regions, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Urban Transportation Planning, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- High Speed Computers in Traffic Analysis and Planning, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- The Future, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Planning and Urban Area Transportation Studies, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Highways and the Future Demand and supply of Metropolitan Transportation, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- The Problems of Planning New Metropolitan Transportation Facilities and Some Computer Applications, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Lambda Alpha - Ely Chapter, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- CATS Progress Report, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Speech to Mid-Atlantic Section of I.T.E., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- A Method of Traffic Assignment to and Urban Network, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Talk to Mr. Muller, Sec. of Commerce, and B. Tallamy, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Future Downtown Chicago Traffic and Transportation Patterns, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Research Findings From a Study of Travel in the Chicago Metropolitan Area, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Talk in Mayor's Office, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Talk to City of Monticello, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Future Travel Demands in the Chicago Region, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Transportation Planning for Central Areas and Stable Characteristics of Urban Travel, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- "Fitting Transportation Systems Plans to Urban Land-Use Projections", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Some Common Pitfalls of Urban Transportation Planning, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- "Public Transportation in Connecticut", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Annual Conference - AIP - The Evolution of Metropolitan Area Transportation Studies and the Organization of the TSTC, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Westchester County Village Officials Association - "The TSTC - What It Is and What Its Work Can Mean to Suburban Communities", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Dartmouth, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- 19th Annual Conference - RPA, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- "Airports in the Over-all Transportation Picture", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Miscellaneous "Promotion" - Congratulatory Notes and Press Clippings, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Interaction of Traffic and Land Use in Urban - How These Apply in Long Range Planning, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- "The TSTC - Ally or Sword of Damocles?", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Miscellaneous, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- "Fitting Urban Transportation Systems to Urban Land Use Projections", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Land Use and Transportation - Old and New Ways of Seeing These, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Spatial Interaction and the Urban-Metropolitan Regional Description, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- "Planning for Improved Transportation in the Tri-State Region", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- The Role of the Automobile in Urban Areas, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- "Techniques for Establishing Units of Measurement of Community Values", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- "The Urban Transportation Problem: Defining the Central Issue", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Advanced Urban Planning and Urbanism Seminar Talk in re Computerized Land Use Transportation Planning, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Metropolitan Regional Council, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- NYU Workshop in Urban Economics, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- "The Urban Transportation Planning Process", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- "Can We Solve the Urban Transportation Problem?", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- "Transportation Problems in the City", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Salzburg Seminar, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 59-64)
- Princeton Engineer: "Creating Feasible Metropolitan Regional Plans", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- "Towards a National Policy for Urban Transportation", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- "Outlook for the Seventies" MRC Annual Meeting, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- "Which City's Transportation System Works Best", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- TAG - Assumptions of Growth (TSRPC Highway Plan), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- "Planning for the Urban Public" Princeton, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- "The Tri-State - UMTA Story", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- "How Can the Census Better Serve the Needs of Metropolitan Area-Wide Transportation Planning?", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Applied Regional Transportation Planning, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- MRC-TV Air Quality Panel: "Energy, Air Quality and Transportation", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- "Commuter Railroads in Metropolitan Transportation Planning:, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Sierra Club (Conn.), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Salzburg Seminar - Notes on Lectures (1969) and 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Salzburg, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Commuter Railroads in Metropolitan Transportation Planning, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Report: Planning for the New York Metropolitan Region, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Toward an Auto-Free Manhattan - Analysis Notes, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1978-1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Martin Mogridge - Paper, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Truck Freight - Milwaukee Talk, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Urban Planning for Indonesia, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- New Jersey Transportation and other, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Lecture Notes CE 268 Spring 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- CE 467, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Princeton University Commencement Program, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Princeton, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous talks, outline, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Newspaper clippings, 1949-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)